[A Splendid Match]
[Episode 28]
I heard that
Second Master Chen
specifically requested a leave of absence
for your wedding with Third Master.
He is rushing back
from Shaanxi now.
This also shows that
Third Master really values
this marriage.
I can rest assured now.
Ms. Tong.
Yes.
Tell everyone to disperse.
Come, follow me.
[Chen-Zhang] [Chen Yanzhang]
[Happiness]
[Chen Yanzhang] [Qin Xianlan]
[Chen Yanwen] [Wang]
[Happiness]
[Chen-Zhang]
[Chen Yanzhang] [Chen Yanyun] [Chen Yanwen]
[Chen Yanpu] [Chen Xuanqing]
This old friend of mine
has been stubborn since she was little.
She can't stand opposition,
nor does she like ostentation from others.
I plan to be more restrained.
I will only say
nice things in front of her.
That's right.
Third Master has two elder brothers.
Both are born of concubines.
Eldest Master
caught malaria
and passed away
at the age of twenty.
Second Master grew up
with Old Madam
and is highly valued.
Now,
he is the Provincial Administration
Commissioner in Shaanxi.
His wife, Qin,
is from the Qin family in Zhending.
Because of her high birth,
she took charge of the household
as soon as she married in.
But because Second Master is posted away
all year round,
Qin has to run back and forth.
She may not
be able to manage the household
indefinitely.
I hope she could keep managing it.
Why?
Don't you want to be
the madam in charge?
I used to think that if I didn't
manage the household,
I would definitely be bullied.
Now I understand.
Managing the household
takes a lot of effort,
and you don't get any thanks for it.
and I even have to
subsidize it with my own money.
With this time and effort,
I'd be better off focusing on managing
my own properties.
Isn't this better than anything?
Well said.
As long as you know
not to fight over that little bit of power
in that mansion,
I haven't raised you in vain.
After Third Master is Fourth Master Chen.
He is Third Master's own young brother.
He also passed the provincial exam
earlier.
But later, for some reason,
he never took the metropolitan exam again.
He just manages the chores in the mansion.
I heard Third Master mention it once.
It should be due to seizure disorder.
Third Master even told you
about this as well?
Since Third Master
has told you all these things,
I don't need to say more.
Presumably,
you know as much as I do.
No.
I want to hear it from you, Grandmother.
Don't you find me annoying?
Of course not.
When you say these things to me,
I still feel
like a child
fearless of everything.
If I do anything wrong,
you will always cover for me.
Silly child.
You are about to get married,
yet you still act so spoiled.
Grandmother,
I can't bear to leave you.
I can't bear
to let you go either.
You are a blessed child.
In the future, with Third Master,
discuss everything
and live a good life together.
[Gu Mansion]
It's raining.
Everyone, be careful.
Don't bump or drop anything.
If anyone makes a mistake tomorrow,
I'll tan their hide!
-Yes!
[Gu]
Hya!
Your Lordship,
what brings you here?
To add some dowry items
for your young lady.
[Gu Mansion]
This... this...
This...
Dezhu!
Baoning.
Go to the Chen family to report the news.
Hurry!
[Fair Morning, Fine Hour]
Wait here.
Yes.
Young Lord Ye, please wait!
Your eyes are so swollen.
You mustn't cry anymore.
Tomorrow, once the veil is on,
I won't see anyone.
My Lady.
Won't the Third Master lift your veil?
Young Lord Ye,
Zhao is getting married tomorrow.
You are a man outside the family.
Please consider
Zhao's reputation.
Reputation?
What's there to fear?
Am I not her uncle?
Young Lord Ye, please don't!
Li Xianhuai!
What's that sound?
Go,
get someone to bring a chair over.
But he is the Young Lord Ye.
Do you want to offend Chen Yanyun?
Hurry and go get a chair!
[Generations of Excellence]
My Lady,
it sounds like it's Young Lord Ye.
♪ Moonlight spills over the lapels of
my gown ♪
♪ My longing receives no reply ♪
♪ Wind rises, silently dissipating
from my heart ♪
♪ That is the morning I missed ♪
♪ Ink stains spread on the letter paper ♪
Don't open it.
♪ Outlining an unfinished poem ♪
Are you feeling better?
♪ Lamplight gently flickers
at the corners of my eyes ♪
♪ Reflecting the empty memories ♪
♪ I gently murmur your name ♪
♪ Like snowflakes falling into the palm ♪
♪ Before I can hold them up
for you to see clearly ♪
I still remember that time...
♪ They have already melted into teardrops
falling into my hands ♪
You came to my coming-of-age ceremony.
I went against my father
♪ I gently write of parting ♪
in front of everyone.
You were the first to step forward
♪ Like fleeting fireflies
losing their trace ♪
and speak for me.
Three people can build
perfect harmony too.
♪ Before I can inscribe the ending ♪
Well said!
♪ It was already destined, in this life,
hard to promise each other ♪
You should be rewarded.
From then on,
I owed you a debt of gratitude.
♪ Worries have built a gate
within my heart ♪
Later,
I took your carriage
♪ Yet the oath will not succumb ♪
to Sili Hutong.
♪ In dreams, I piece together
the lingering warmth ♪
You also helped me
give my father
♪ Whose kiss does the deep love trap? ♪
a show of force,
helping me find my footing
♪ The chessboard, black and white pieces
like stars ♪
in that unfamiliar home.
♪ I play alone until dawn breaks ♪
Even later,
♪ This single move has trapped time ♪
you helped me many more times.
♪ And trapped me as well ♪
Don't talk about me helping you.
Let's just talk about you helping me.
Before the palace coup,
you rushed back to the capital
from Tongzhou
to bring me news,
taking a huge personal risk.
You were even willing to
risk your life for me.
Yet you say
you don't have even a little bit of
fondness for me?
That's different.
How is it different?
Do you resent that I never
explicitly stated I wanted to marry you?
No.
Ye Xian.
I'm willing to
risk my life for you.
But it's not only romantic love
that makes someone risk their life.
Friendship can too.
Friends.
Just friends?
♪ The long night stretches
beyond the street ♪
♪ Longing piles up like snowdrifts ♪
♪ I gaze at the moon, praying
for a dream ♪
There is no umbrella in my room.
It's cold outside.
♪ In the dream, your footsteps are light ♪
Put this on.
♪ Softly, I gaze at that silhouette ♪
♪ Like the sunset sinking
behind distant ridges ♪
♪ Using all the strength of my
remaining years ♪
♪ I could not hold you back
to say goodbye ♪
You might
♪ Gently, I sigh at that scene ♪
not believe it.
♪ Like a swing still in an empty
courtyard ♪
Actually,
since I was little,
♪ Before I can grasp the past tightly ♪
I haven't had many friends
apart from my family.
♪ Only memories remain, drifting lightly ♪
I could even say
that you are my only friend.
Others say
you have an eccentric and odd temper.
But I know
that it's not oddness.
You just
don't know how to act.
I'm the same.
I'm the eldest daughter,
but I've always
had to be away from my parents.
No matter how well others treat me,
I still feel
like a piece of my heart
is forever missing.
As for being tricky and eccentric,
and arrogant,
it's just because I was so scared
that I had to put on a brave face.
You don't know.
For so many times,
when I look at you,
it's like looking in a mirror.
It's like looking at another me.
Ye Xian.
To me,
you are extremely special.
But...
I cannot love you.
Because we are both that kind of people
who are panicked inside,
but on the outside,
are stubborn and tough.
We like to act tough
and say things we don't mean.
We clearly want to be cared for,
but dare not say it out loud.
Ye Xian,
I've lived for eighteen years,
and I feel tired every single day.
I simply cannot be
together with another version of myself.
Then if you marry Chen Jiuheng,
won't you be tired?
Maybe I will be.
But
I am willing.
Do you love Chen Jiuheng that much?
[Fair Morning, Fine Hour]
Mother，
look at the characters on this screen.
[Fair Morning, Fine Hour]
What kind of "uncle" is this?
This is clearly the feeling between
a man and a woman!
Shut up!
Do you have a death wish?
Lord Chen.
[Fair Morning, Fine Hour]
Thank you for your trouble, Madam.
It is my duty.
Lord Chen,
this...
Got it.
You may leave now.
Yes.
My Lord.
[Marquis Changxing's Mansion]
No wonder I couldn't
find you anywhere.
I knew it.
You came here again.
My Lord?
My Lord!
[Fair Morning, Fine Hour]
Ye Xian.
Today, I will spare you once.
I'll just attribute it to your youth
and recklessness,
and you forgetting the proprieties.
But remember,
this is the last time.
Gu Jinzhao.
I've added to your dowry items.
To your dowry items.
I only hope that from now on,
year after year, you may have
your wish fulfilled,
and have a good day every day.
It's just that in those years and days,
there will be no me.
[Generations of Excellence]
Over there.
Higher, higher.
-How about this?
-Alright.
Further in.
-Is it okay here?
-Yeah.
Okay, hold it there.
Okay.
Old Madam,
do you think today
the Chen family will
change their minds
and break the engagement?
Nonsense.
If the Chen family really dares to
cancel the engagement,
wouldn't that be admitting
defeat to Ye Xian?
Chen Yanyun would be
the first to lose face.
However,
if Zhao marries into their family,
I'm afraid she will suffer.
True.
How could
an important minister tolerate this?
Just wait and see.
If Zhao
loses respect in front of Lord Chen,
our family and the Chen family
will become distant again.
This marriage alliance,
on the surface,
seems like we're climbing
up the social ladder.
But in fact,
we are just offending people.
[Gu Mansion]
Play.
Who told you to stop?
Play!
[Gu Mansion]
[Liang Lin, Director of
the Court of State Ceremonial]
Direcor Liang.
[Chang Tinglan,
Director of Hanlin Academy]
Director Chang.
Dezhao.
[He Wenrui, Compilor of the Hanlin Academy
and Imperial Tutor]
Lord He.
Hurry!
Play it!
Play it! Hurry!
Combing hair, tying knots,
husband and wife of one heart!
Then I will
wait for you outside.
Thank you, Grandmother.
Zhao, you look so beautiful.
After such a disgraceful scene last night,
she is still so composed.
If you keep gossiping,
get out.
Once she's married,
who will protect you?
Could it be the wedding procession
has arrived?
They're here, they're here!
Who have come?
A lot of high-ranking officials have come.
Besides Lord Chen,
there's also the Director of
the Hanlin Academy,
and the Vice Minister of Personnel.
Oh right,
Grand Secretary He's younger brother
also came.
They said his title is Imperial something.
Imperial Tutor?
That's an official close to the Emperor,
a future Grand Secretary.
Such a grand display.
Looks like everything is fine.
Everything is fine.
Second Master requests your presence
in the front hall immediately.
Co... coming right away.
-Coming right away.
-Watch...
Watch your step.
Mother,
I have put on my wedding dress too.
I was always afraid of
following in your footsteps.
Afraid that great joy
would ultimately lead to emptiness.
But somehow,
I still want to give it a try in the end.
Fortunately,
he is not just anyone.
He is the one who is willing to
crouch down and listen to me,
and keep my preferences
in mind.
Mother,
I will live the life
you once hoped for.
The bride is here!
♪ A good moment is strewn with starlight ♪
♪ Flames burn away
the frost of bygone days ♪
♪ Reflections tremble,
hearts beat in unison ♪
♪ Candlelight weaves the web of fate ♪
The couple bids farewell to the parents!
♪ Petal shadows
trace the lines of your face ♪
♪ Fleeting light
sketches the shape of fate ♪
♪ Footsteps fall lightly,
yet feelings can't be concealed ♪
♪ In a backward glance,
a few hidden feelings slip through ♪
Second bow!
♪ Ask the passing time
whether it has forgotten ♪
Third bow!
♪ The moonlight of our first encounter ♪
♪ Year after year,
it etches your likeness ♪
♪ Count the faint shimmer
of the starry river ♪
♪ Yet none compares
to the gentle light in your eyes ♪
♪ At last, I see the galaxy
shimmering and swaying ♪
♪ Reflected in our eyes ♪
♪ I'll be with you forever ♪
Fourth bow!
♪ And enjoy
the beautiful scenery with you ♪
♪ For all the days of our lives,
our love will endure ♪
The bride is leaving the house!
♪ Soft whispers turn into verse ♪
♪ Beneath the bright moonlight,
you and I stand together ♪
♪ Hand in hand, our love deepens
with each passing year ♪
♪ By your side,
I'll follow wherever your heart leads ♪
♪ Ask the passing time
whether it has forgotten ♪
♪ The moonlight of our first encounter ♪
♪ Year after year,
it etches your likeness ♪
♪ Count the faint shimmer
of the starry river ♪
♪ Yet none compares
to the gentle light in your eyes ♪
♪ At last, I see the galaxy
shimmering and swaying ♪
♪ Reflected in our eyes ♪
♪ I'll be with you forever ♪
♪ And enjoy
the beautiful scenery with you ♪
♪ For all the days of our lives,
our love will endure ♪
♪ Ask the passing time
whether it has forgotten ♪
♪ The moonlight of our first encounter ♪
♪ Year after year,
it etches your likeness ♪
♪ Count the faint shimmer
of the starry river ♪
♪ Yet none compares
to the gentle light in your eyes ♪
♪ At last, I see the galaxy
shimmering and swaying ♪
♪ Reflected in our eyes ♪
♪ I'll be with you forever ♪
On this auspicious day,
Lord Chen Yanyun, the Grand Secretary
♪ And enjoy
the beautiful scenery with you ♪
and Gu Jinzhao, legitimate daughter
of the fourth branch of the Gu Mansion,
have chosen this fine day
to form a marital union!
[Gu Mansion]
♪ For all the days of our lives,
our love will endure ♪
May it be a tale of harmony
between two mansions!
The bridal sedan arrives at the door,
flutes and drums fill the road.
May the neighbors who stop to watch
share in the joy of this ceremony!
May the newlyweds a harmonious marriage!
May your fortune and longevity
be boundless!
[Ji's Silk and Satin]
[Spirit Tablet of Ye Guangsheng,
the Late Marquis Changxing,
Conferred by the Great Yan]
[Spirit Tablet of Ye Guangsheng,
the Late Marquis Changxing,
Conferred by the Great Yan]
[Spirit Tablet of Ye Guangsheng,
the Late Marquis Changxing,
Conferred by the Great Yan]
[Spirit Tablet of Ye Guangsheng,
the Late Marquis Changxing,
Conferred by the Great Yan]
The old Marquis has passed away
unexpectedly.
What's wrong?
We've encountered a funeral procession.
The deceased takes precedence.
Let's make way for them.
My Lady, Third Master is up ahead.
[Spirit Tablet of Ye Guangsheng,
the Late Marquis Changxing,
Conferred by the Great Yan]
Make way!
[Spirit Tablet of Ye Guangsheng,
the Late Marquis Changxing,
Conferred by the Great Yan]
[Messages of safety]
♪ Once I wrote of spring and fall ♪
♪ Yet fell through time's abyss ♪
♪ Every shade turned bitter ♪
♪ Every longing became sorrow ♪
♪ I've seen through right and wrong ♪
♪ Old vows washed away like ash ♪
My Lady,
The funeral procession has
given way to us.
♪ True devotion is knowing
the freedom within your heart♪
I feel really bad for them.
♪ Word by word, hand in hand ♪
♪ My heart grows cold like rust ♪
♪ The stars send you far away ♪
Hya.
♪ Yet one thought still remains ♪
♪ You share bright days with another ♪
♪ I walk with my lonely shadow ♪
♪ Filling every broken fold
with memories of us ♪
♪ We once drank to talk of love and hate ♪
♪ But we fell into
the deep ditch of rumors ♪
♪ Meeting and parting were like
moves on a chessboard ♪
♪ Every heartfelt word ended as a fault ♪
[Spirit Tablet of Ye Guangsheng,
the Late Marquis Changxing,
♪ Seen the sun rise and the moon set ♪
Conferred by the Great Yan]
♪ Only sigh that we are no longer
on the same path ♪
♪ One wrong choice drove
my old friend away like a drifting bird ♪
[Memorial]
♪ With every step, I look back ♪
Let's go!
♪ My heart grows cold like rust ♪
♪ The stars send you far away ♪
[Baiwei Restaurant]
♪ Yet one thought still remains ♪
♪ You share bright days with another ♪
♪ I walk with my lonely shadow ♪
[Memorial]
♪ Filling every broken fold
with memories of us ♪
[Spirit Tablet of Ye Guangsheng,
the Late Marquis Changxing,
Conferred by the Great Yan]
Bow to Heaven and Earth!
[Chen Yanzhang,
Second Master of the Chen family]
Bow to parents!
Husband and wife bow to each other!
An imperial edict has arrived!
[Imperial Edict]
By the grace of Heaven, the Emperor
decrees:
I have inherited the great mandate
to rule over all directions.
I promote education to rectify
moral relations
and value titles to distinguish
good and evil.
As for the rules of the inner chambers,
they are crucial to morals.
A woman's honor comes from her husband.
This is in line with the state's
system.
Chen Yanyun,
Grand Secretary of the Eastern Cabinet
and Left Vice Minister of Revenue,
now has a wife, Gu.
[Imperial Edict]
Gu has made contributions to the people.
With her virtuous and gentle nature,
she is now conferred of
the second-rank titled lady.
Gu shall abide by this.
May you respectfully accept
this grand decree
and forever establish a virtuous model.
Respect this!
Long live His Majesty!
Madam Chen, please receive the decree.
I
thank His Majesty for his profound grace!
Usually,
only when an official makes a contribution
does his wife get an imperial title.
Yet His Majesty decreed on the day
of Jiuheng's wedding
to grant Gu an imperial title.
This is truly unprecedented in Great Yan.
Jiuheng is a diligent official.
His Majesty naturally trusts him.
As for Gu,
I only hope she is worthy of it.
That coronet is so heavy.
My neck is about to break.
Thank goodness
you were here to help me take it off
and redo my hair.
So much more comfortable now.
My Lady,
you were so glorious today.
I don't know why,
but I've been feeling very anxious.
Maybe you're just nervous about
getting married.
No.
Earlier when we were on the street,
and ran into a funeral procession,
did you see clearly
whose family it was?
I felt it was bad luck,
so I didn't look at all.
I just saw a patch of white.
I think
I heard Ye Xian's voice.
I really didn't see him.
My Lady,
you might be overthinking.
Last night,
didn't His Lordship
come to see you?
Madam!
Third Master was worried
you might be hungry,
so he ordered us to bring
the banquet food up first.
Come on.
Thank you all
for coming in person to congratulate me.
I
would like to toast you all!
-Congratulations!
Congratulations!
Cheers.
Congratulations.
Congratulations, Old Madam.
My Lady, this is delicious.
Eat more if you like it.
I think
you are right.
Ye Xian just came to see me last night,
so nothing bad should have happened.
My Lady, I feel
you shouldn't worry about Young Lord Ye.
You should worry about Third Master.
Worry about Third Master?
Why?
Last night,
there was such a fuss.
Aren't you afraid Third Master
will get angry?
He might be
a bit upset, I suppose.
But it wasn't directed at me.
You're already eating the feast
he sent over,
and you still worry he'd be petty?
True.
I heard the servants say earlier
that Third Master is very caring.
He made such a big show
of sending this food over.
It's it because he was worried
that the people in the mansion would
look down on me?
Eat slowly.
After you finish,
go to the front hall.
There are many people today.
Don't let him drink too much,
and send him some hangover soup as well.
Okay.
Congratulations.
Thank you, Mentor.
Please.
Come on.
Marquis Changxing has passed away.
You must have heard.
Yes.
His Majesty intends
for Ye Xian to inherit the title.
That cannot happen, Mentor.
We finally
waited for Marquis Changxing to die.
How could we let Ye Xian
inherit the title?
I heard that last night
he caused trouble for you again.
Just the struggle of a cornered beast.
It's nothing to worry about.
Please, please.
Come on, have another glass.
This...
Jiuheng, you've been resting at home
for a long time, right?
Go back to Hall of Literary Profundity
in a few days.
Great.
Quick, Jiuheng!
Thank you, Mentor.
Xuanweng's high regard for Jiuheng
is truly unquestionable.
Drink!
Drink, drink.
Mentor, your kindness to me
is like a second chance at life.
It makes me deeply ashamed.
We are teacher and student.
No need for formalities.
Come on.
Let's drink.
Come on, drink.
Please.
Come on.
Good wine.
Drink more tonight.
Xuruo, you look like
you have something on your mind.
No.
I...
I'm happy.
Happy?
What kind of happiness looks like that?
Xuruo!
Let him be!
Come on,
let's keep drinking.
Let's drink up.
Come on, drink.
Gu Jinzhao.
[A Splendid Match]